<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>games on manueljimenezs</title><link>https://manueljimenezs.github.io/tags/games/</link><description>manueljimenezs (games)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://manueljimenezs.github.io/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Miyoo Mini: A great handheld improved by a great community</title><link>https://manueljimenezs.github.io/2022/08/miyoo-mini-a-great-handheld-improved-by-a-great-community/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://manueljimenezs.github.io/2022/08/miyoo-mini-a-great-handheld-improved-by-a-great-community/</guid><description>&lt;p>The truth is that I was keeping an eye on this device for a long time. I hesitated a few months before I took the plunge. And I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier 😄.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a small retro console. Retro handhelds have been around for a while, but in this case the build quality, the price and the performance make it a wonderful candy. You can find them with a price tag of 50-60$ in Aliexpress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://manueljimenezs.github.io/img/2022-08-28-miyoo-mini/miyoo.jpg" alt="The Miyoo Mini is VERY small. Photo for comparison.">
&lt;figcaption>The Miyoo Mini is VERY small. Photo for comparison.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This handheld comes with a &lt;strong>640x480 IPS display&lt;/strong>, and it&amp;rsquo;s GORGEOUS. No photo can show how good this screen looks, colors just pop right out of the screen. The screen is the same as the ones that the Blackberry Bold 9990. It also features a &lt;strong>1.2GHz&lt;/strong> processor with &lt;strong>128MB RAM&lt;/strong> and it&amp;rsquo;s crazy how such little power can provide.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you have messed a little bit with Retroarch, you can see it has a lot of potential and in this device it has a lot to say. The Miyoo Mini comes with a custom linux firmware made by Miyoo. I works okay but it has some caveats here and there. Retroarch is running at half the resolution so games appear a little blurry.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, to get the most of it, some fans developed a custom firmware called Onion OS. It includes more emulators, ports (you can run Doom on it, of course) and a wide variety of configurations to make games run well. Everything is made easier. When you exit a game or turn off the console, it automatically saves the current state of the game so you cant get back to it exactly to the point you left it. Loading games is very fast here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Retroarch now runs at native resolution so you can appreciate the crispiness:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://manueljimenezs.github.io/img/2022-08-28-miyoo-mini/miyoo_2.jpg" alt="In GBC, a grid filter makes it look almost real">
&lt;figcaption>In GBC, a grid filter makes it look almost real.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There is a wide variety of platforms to choose from, basically everything before (and including) PSOne: GBA, Neo-Geo, Game Boy Color, SNES, MS-DOS, Amiga, MAME and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the new update of the Retroarch core DosBox-Pure you can even run Windows 98 on this thing. 🤯&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="https://manueljimenezs.github.io/img/2022-08-28-miyoo-mini/miyoo_3.jpg" alt="Booting Windows 98">
&lt;figcaption>Booting Windows 98.&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you like playing old games on the go, this is ticking almost all the boxes, so go for it!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>